Luis Felipe López Montes

Full-stack web developer

PHP, Symfony, ReactJS, SQL, TDD, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, JIRA, SCRUM. # Python, Jupyter, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, FastAPI, Google Compute

Software engineer with wide experience in web development, both backend and frontend. Passionate about sport, nature and coding. With objectives, among others, to achieve stability within a company in which I can put my skills into practice, as well as being able to carry out different projects in which to focus my motivation.





flopezmontes98@gmail.com











PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Aircury. Full-stack web developer. 08/2022-10/2023, 03/2024 - Now (Remote)

I worked for a UK-based customer (CEC) in the UK education sector, following Agile **SCRUM** and using **JIRA** for task management. My role involved developing the tasks required by the customer within each sprint while adhering to best practices such as **TDD** and **BDD** methodologies.

These tasks included **full-stack** development, such as creating new features, sections, and more on various web applications, using ReactJS and PHP-Symfony, as well as database management with Doctrine and PostgreSQL. I also performed data integration tasks between Salesforce and various APIs.

Additionally, code reviews were conducted for my teammates' tickets as well as collaboration with our support and testing teams, ensuring quality and consistency throughout the company's workflow. In addition, I also implemented automated tasks and pipelines in **Jenkins** for data integration from external platforms.

We worked with Docker environments running on AWS, along with Kubernetes for container orchestration and management, and Jenkins for automating the deployment process. Version control was conducted with GitHub.

Strategic Thinking. Full-stack web developer. 05/2021 – 12/2021 (Remote)

Full-stack development using Vanilla JS, HTML and CSS, using Google Firebase Firestore Database and Materialize.css. Co-founder of https://anetva2021.web.app/. and maintenance of https://totalhse.web.app/

University of Vigo. Intern. 02/2020 – 08/2020 (Ourense, Spain)

I carried out maintenance tasks and managed a computer space for study and learning through ICTs. Constantly dealing with students and employees who needed help with both computer and printer problems.

MQL5.COM. Freelancer. 12/2019 – 12/2020 (Remote)

Development of operational scripts in Forex markets, based on technical market indicators. Direct contact with customers.

Banco Santander, Bank clerk, 07/2018 – 08/2018 (Bilbao, Spain)

LANGUAGES

English: Professional (C1) French: Intermediate (B2)

Spanish: Native Galician: Native

EDUCATION

10/2023-12/2023 Data Science Bootcamp Le Wagon, Zürich (Python, SQL, Jupyter, Matplotlib, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, Google Compute, Hugging Face, MLflow, EastAPI, ChatGPT)

2016-2022 **Bachelor in Computer Engineering** University of Vigo

2016-2022 **Bachelor in Business** Administration University of Vigo

PORTFOLIO

Click to see my portfolio!